(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T17:42:14.343056",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
今 幸せなのは 朗らかなあなたの温もりが
Now, what makes me so happy is your gentle warmth
陰りゆく私の心をあの月のように
shining upon my darkening heart like the moon,
優しく照らして そしてすべて包んでくれた
gently lighting it up and embracing everything.
迷いを晴らしてくれた
You cleared away all my doubts.
あなたがいなければ 私は星のように輝けないまま
Without you, I'd remain unable to shine like a star.
愛の小さな歌は ただあなたが聴いてくれるだけでいい
This little song of love... it's enough if you just listen.
今 心に描いた 光に満ちている 明日へと私は
Toward a tomorrow filled with the light painted in my heart,
一人夢を追い続けながらも彷徨った
I wandered while continuing to chase my dream alone.
あなたが居てくれたから 続けられた笑顔の日々送れた
Because you were there, I could spend smiling days.
あなたがいなければ 私は流れ星よ
Without you, I'm just a shooting star.
愛の小さな歌よ
Oh, little song of love,
あなたにとって忘れがたい人でありたいの
I want to be someone unforgettable to you.
夜は静寂で 肌を探している 少し眠たい目と月の音色
The night is silent, the wind seeking my skin, with sleepy eyes and the moonlight's tone.
愛しています 骨が溶けそうなほど
I love you, so much that my bones feel like melting.
あなたがいなければ 私は星のように輝けぬまま
Without you, I'd remain unable to shine like a star.
今 幸せなのは 朗らかな あなたの温もりが
Now, what makes me happy is the warmth of your cheerful presence
陰りゆく 私の 心を あの 月のように
Illuminating my fading heart gently like that moon
優しく 照らし そして すべて 包んでくれたから 続けていられたわ
and completely embracing me, allowing me to keep going.
笑顔の日々を くれた あなたが いなければ
If you weren't here to give me smiling days,
私は 星のように 輝けないまま 愛の 小さな 歌は
I wouldn't shine like a star. This small song of love
ただ あなたが 聴いてくれる だけ で いい
is enough if just you listen to it.
今 心に 描いた 光に 満ちている 明日へと 私は
Now, toward a tomorrow full of light drawn in my heart, I
ひとり 夢を 追い続けながらも 彷徨えたわ
wandered while continuing to chase my dreams alone.
あなたが いてくれた から 続けられたわ 笑顔の日々を送れた
Because you were there for me, I could keep living days of smiles.
あなたががいなければ 私は 流れ星よ
If you weren't here, I would be a shooting star.
愛の 小さな歌よ あなたにとって 忘れがたい 人で ありたいの
Oh small song of love, I want to be someone unforgettable to you.
夜は 静寂で 風が 肌を 探している 少し 眠たい 目と 月の音色
The night is silent, the wind searches the skin, with sleepy eyes and the moon's tone.
愛しています 骨が 溶けそう な ほど あなたが いなければ 私は
I love you so much it feels like my bones are melting. If you weren't here, I would still
星のように 輝けぬまま 愛の 小さな 歌は ただ あなたが 聴いてくれるだけで いい
be unable to shine like a star. The small song of love is enough if just you listen to it.
今 心に 描いた 光に 満ちている 明日へと 私は
Now, toward a tomorrow full of light drawn in my heart, I
ひとり 夢を 追い続けながらも 彷徨えたわ
wandered while continuing to chase my dreams alone.
あなたが いてくれた から 続けられたわ 笑顔の日々を送れた あなたがいなければ 私は星よ
Because you were there for me, I could keep living days of smiles. If you weren't here, I would be a star.
What is this?
Lagi, lagi nyanyi sedih-sedih, tapi kok, tapi kok banyak asap sih? Kenapa sih? Ih, menyebalkan!
Singing sad songs again, but why is there so much smoke? Why? Ugh, how annoying!
Semuanya! Bisa liat menang enggak di sini? Hehe, heee!
Everyone! Can you see if I win here? Hehe, hee!
Moona Hoshinova from Hololive Indonesia Generation 1!
Akhirnya, akhirnya setelah menunggu 17 tahun lamanya. Maksudnya 17 bulan.
Finally, after waiting for 17 long years. I mean 17 months!
Moona akhirnya bisa bergerak, tidak gepek lagi!
Moona can finally move, no more being flat!
Oke, jangan lupa ya, ambil screenshot dan tweet sebanyak-banyaknya dengan hashtag #MoonaHoshinova3D!
Okay, don't forget to take screenshots and tweet as much as you can with the hashtag #MoonaHoshinova3D!
Nah, ini Moona kan pengen nyanyi dan bergerak sebanyak mungkin nih. Jadi, tonton sampai akhir ya! Kalau begitu, langsung saja ke lagu berikutnya!
Well, Moona wants to sing and move as much as possible, so watch until the end! If so, let's move right on to the next song!
Oke yuk, Blue Clapper!
Okay, let's go, Blue Clapper!
Te wo ageteteku clap your hands umi no mukou made
Raise your hand, clap your hands beyond the sea,
clap your hands todokimasu you ni
clap your hands so that it reaches you,
Te wo tatakou te wo tatakou hora issho ni everybody
let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands, look, everyone together,
clap your hands sora no mukou made
clap your hands beyond the sky,
clap your hands hibikimasu you ni
clap your hands so that it echoes,
Te wo tatakou te wo tatakou
let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands,
Hikarou bokutachi no mirai
our future shining with light!
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light shines upon our future.
始めようか さあ diving
Shall we start? C'mon, let's dive in.
待っても意味ない timing
There's no point in waiting for the timing.
あの魚みたいに swimming swimming
Like that fish, swimming, swimming.
引き寄せるの lighting
The lighting draws us in,
まだ見えないよ maybe
Maybe we can't see it yet.
この先には何があるのか？
What lies ahead of us?
まだ早いよ take it
It's still too early, just take it.
追い付くまで shaking
Shaking until we catch up.
でもたまに止まって thinking thinking
But sometimes stopping to think, think.
変えてみて示す change
Showing a change,
ふみ出すのだよ stepping
Stepping forward,
掴んでみせるよ キラキラ my dream
I'll grasp my sparkling dream.
叶う日まで story 繋ぐから
Connecting the story until the day it comes true,
だって君に ずっと見てほしいから
Because I want you to keep watching me.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
重なる wave 世界を揺らし
Overlapping waves shake the world!
今日はいらない breaking
Today we don't need breaks,
理性壊せ breaking
Breaking down reason, breaking.
何時でもいいでしょ？四六時中
Anytime is fine, right? 24/7,
君は何を feeling？
What are you feeling?
解き放て sparking
Unleash the sparking,
闇に放つ レーザービーム
Laser beams released into the darkness.
鳴らし続けて stage 作るから
Keeping it ringing to build the stage,
だって君に もっと見てほしいから
Because I want you to watch me even more.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
重なる wave 世界を揺らし
Overlapping waves shake the world!
終わりがあること 既に i know
I already know that everything must end,
でもまだまだ 泳ぎ足りないのか
But we still haven't had enough of swimming.
give me crazy
までレイジー？
Are you like lazy?
次元混ざり合うの
Dimensions blending together,
全て塗り替える blue
Blue that repaints everything.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light shines upon our future.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light shines upon our future.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light shines upon our future.
さあ鳴らせ
Now, let it ring!
世界を揺らせ
Shake the world!
Yeah!
Oh yeah!
Ha!
終わりが来る事 既に i know
I already know that everything must end,
でもまだまだ 泳ぎ足りないの
But we still haven't had enough of swimming.
give me crazy
まじでレイジー？
Are you like lazy?
次元混ざり合うの
Dimensions blending together,
全て塗り替える blue
Blue that repaints everything.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light shines upon our future.
手を上げて
Raise your hands,
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届きますように
clap your hands so they reach far,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, everybody together,
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands so they resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
clap your hands, clap your hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light shines upon our future.
It's time to take 3D anniversary one for listening BLUE CLAPPER!
It's time to take the 3D anniversary one for listening BLUE CLAPPER!
As you can see, this song is so hype!
I just can't stop jumping!
I want to use this song for hyping
because, you know, jumping while singing is fun, even though I just like "hugh, hugh, hugh"...
because, you know, jumping while singing is fun, even though I just go "hugh, hugh, hugh"...
but that's fine! That's fine!
Anyway, have you guys seen... have you guys seen this? It's a Moona!
Lucu kan? Lucu kan? Lucu kan?
Cute, right? Cute, right? Cute, right?
Jadi, next Moona bakal menyanyikan lagu sambil diliatin Mumo.
So, next Moona will sing a song while being watched by Mumo.
Jadi, ya gitulah, kita... kita nyanyi sambil joget, terus nanti ada Mumo lagi di sekitar situ.
So, yeah, like that, we... we sing while dancing, and then Mumo will be around there.
Kalian nikmati aja, oke?
Just enjoy it, okay?
Alright, Mumo, kamu ke depannya. Shh!
Alright, Mumo, go forward. Shh!
Alright, you guys ready? All right! Again, music, start!
Alright, you guys ready? Alright! Again, music, start!
かねて憧れてた
I'd long adored you,
追いかけてた
and chased after you,
いつまでもそれ言いたかった
and I'd always wanted to say that.
完璧なあなた
You, who are so flawless,
嫌いになった
grew to hate me.
同じように愛をもらって
Receiving love just the same,
いつからか傘が開いてた
ever since our umbrellas opened up.
いつあたりだって知りたかった
I wanted to know what kind of time it was.
ねぇメイビー 神様はしれん与え強くなれよと
Hey, maybe God gave us trials to make us stronger—
うるさい鼓動なんて嘘すぎわかってるけど
such noisy heartbeats are lies, I know that, but...
かわいいとか持てたいとか
Wanting to be cute, wanting to be popular,
諦めないの女の子だし潮らしく猫かぶり
not giving up because I'm a girl, acting modest and playing innocent—
オンリーワンだよ愛してね生き方は無限にある
I'm your one and only! Love me. There are infinite ways to live,
落としそうな大きな声小さな言葉いじらしく猫かぶり
with a voice so loud it might drop, and tiny words, acting so cute and playing innocent—
私らしくいこう今じゃない人生生きよう
let's live true to ourselves, living a life we aren't living right now.
だって理想を言えば君がなくてないもの全部欲しくって
Because if I'm being ideal, you lack nothing, and I wanted everything.
鏡を見たあってため息
Looking in the mirror, I let out a sigh...
あなただって悩んでいた知らなかったみんな同じだと知った
You were troubled too, I didn't know; I learned that everyone is the same.
ピンとハートが揺れていくメイビー神様は楽しんでる
Our hearts are trembling in sync. Hey, maybe God is having fun!
予測できない人を私はそれ以上に楽しんでやるぜ
A person who can't be predicted—I'll enjoy them even more than that!
勉強とか星屑とか
Studying, stardust,
諦めないの女の子だし元気よく愛嬌よく
not giving up because I'm a girl, being energetic and charming—
隣にはグロり進んでいて明日の分愛せるの
marching proudly right beside you, able to love tomorrow's share too.
母さんがくれたアドバイスもしやはりきて
The advice my mother gave me—maybe I tried too hard,
ミスしても私らしくいこう胸張っていきる
but even if I make mistakes, let's live true to myself with my head held high.
空を見上げれば心があたたかかれていたんだ
When I looked up at the sky, my heart had been warmed.
好きに行ってる言いたくない
Saying whatever you want... I don't want to say it!
神様は夢与えれば壊れるために
If God gives dreams, it's so they can break—
サンキューの伝えてやるよ最後まで
I'll say "Thank you" right until the very end!
付き合ってもらうよ雨はやんで傘を閉じた
You're going to go out with me! The rain stopped, and I closed my umbrella.
今まで見えてなかった景色と透明が反射して世界を照らした
The scenery and transparency I couldn't see until now reflected and illuminated the world.
胸踊るかわいいとかもてたいとか諦めないの女の子だし
My heart dances! Wanting to be cute, wanting to be popular, not giving up because I'm a girl—
潮らしく猫かぶりナンバーワンでしょ愛してね
acting modest and playing innocent. I'm number one, right? Love me!
生き方は無限にある音のそんな小さな言葉
There are infinite ways to live, with sounds and tiny words like that—
いじらしく猫かぶり私らしくいこう
acting so cute and playing innocent, let's live true to ourselves.
今じゃない人生生きよう
Living a life we aren't living right now.
神様は夢与えれば壊れるために
If God gives dreams, it's so they can break—
サンキューの伝えてやるよ最後まで
I'll say 'Thank you' right until the very end!
付き合ってもらうよ雨はやんで傘を閉じた今まで見えてなかった景色と透明が反射して世界を照らした胸踊る
You're going to go out with me! The rain stopped, and I closed my umbrella. The scenery and transparency I couldn't see until now reflected and illuminated the world. My heart dances!
Yey!
Yay!
Akhirnya...
Finally...
So,
I am having fun.
Gimana, gimana, gimana? Suka enggak, suka enggak?
How is it? Do you like it?
You guys like it?
Yey!
Yay!
Okay! I will...
Moona milih lagu ini karena kan Moona ingin menunjukan sisi idolnya Moona. Benar.
Moona chose this song because Moona wanted
to show her idol side. Right.
Buktinya Moona berhasil menunjukan...
And proof that Moona successfully showed...
dengan karya... yah, keimutannya Moona. I am cute.
...with her work... well, Moona's cuteness.
I am cute.
Hey guys! I am having fun. Are you guys having fun?
Hey guys! I am having fun.
Are you guys having fun?
Yeah! Of course, of course. It's... it's so nice.
Yeah! Of course, of course.
It's... it's so nice.
It's so nice being here.
I am in my own... uh... bedroom right now.
I know, I know. Who is streaming? Who is like literal dancing performance in the bedroom?
I know, I know. Who is streaming?
Who is doing a literal dancing performance?
Well, now you have me. Yeah.
Okay! Jadi Moona mau kenalin nih... kan biasanya kan kalian cuma ngeliat di kaya pagi Moona gitu kan. Sekilas doang. Jadi Moona mau nunjukin...
Okay! So Moona wants to introduce this...
Just a glimpse. So Moona wants to show...
keseluruhan dari kamarnya Moona. Yey!
...the whole room of Moona's. Yay!
Very like it. Yeah.
Jadi kita mulai dari... dari... dari sini deh kayaknya.
So we'll start from... from... from here, I
guess.
Kalian lihat gorden... Ini... ini yang beli mamanya Moona ya. Biasa kan kalau gorden-gorden, gorden Indonesia kayak gini ya kalian, kalian bisa lihat banyaklah di... di... di tempat penjualan online gitu ya.
You see the curtains... This... this was
bought by Moona's mom. Indonesian curtains
look like this, you can see a lot of them
in online stores.
Terus di sini tuh ada... ada buku-bukunya Moona. Kan Moona pernah cerita kalau misalnya Moona itu suka buku gitu.
And then here there are... Moona's books.
Moona's told stories before about how
Moona likes books.
Terus ada juga, gimana? Ini...
And there's also, how is it? This...
And you guys see that... uh... one of my song... uh... I put my... my jacket in there.
And you guys see that... uh... one of
my songs... uh... I put my... my jacket
in there.
Ichi no Ji-sana Uta and...
'Ichi no Chi-sana Uta' and...
and also... Height-Side! Yay!
...and also 'High Tide'! Yay!
And also we have these. We have these picture. I love it very much.
And also we have these. We have these
pictures. I love them very much.
It's from YariMama and LamaMama. Yeah, thank you!
It's from Yari Mama and Lama Mama.
Yeah, thank you!
So once I saw, 'Oh, it's so nice. I really like it.'
So once I saw, 'Oh, it's so nice.
I really like it.'
And also I have these... my... usual for doing my homework and also make-uping.
And also I have these... my... usual place
for doing my homework and also putting on
makeup.
I have my precious... uh... streaming PC. It's also this chair.
I have my precious... uh... streaming PC.
And also this chair.
And I also have my...  a lot of, you know, tea.
And I also have my... a lot of, you know,
tea.
Because... Because why not? Why not? Right?
Because... Because why not?
Why not? Right?
Yeah.
Ugh... And I also have this... my bedroom. But yeah.
Ugh... And I also have this... my bedroom.
But yeah.
Dan, kan kalau misalnya bingung, 'Wah, Moona... Moona kalau streaming gitu kan, pasti... pasti duduknya itu... uh... kayak... kayak warteg.'
And, if you guys are wondering, 'Wah,
Moona... when Moona streams, surely...
surely her sitting posture is... uh...
like... like in a warteg.'
Benar! Benar! Jadi akhirnya Moona bisa menunjukkan ke kalian kalau cara duduk Moona kalau sambil makan adalah...
Right! Right! So finally Moona can show
you guys how Moona sits when she eats is...
Gitu, teman-teman. That's how you do it! Yeah!
Like this, friends. That's how you do it!
Yeah!
It's the best! No!
No!
Well... Well, that's... that's... um... why we can show in my room.
Well... Well, that's... that's... um...
why we can show in my room.
I want to tell you that... um... we have a lot of things, you know.
I want to tell you that... um... we have
a lot of things, you know.
But first of all, I want to show you my body.
But first of all, I want to show you
my body.
Oh, yeah. Look at that! Look at that! Sheeeesh!
Oh, yeah. Look at that! Look at that!
Sheeeesh!
Nice, isn't it? It's wiggle-wiggle. Yeah.
Wiggle-wiggle, everything is wiggle-wiggle. And... and also look at my hair. Look at my hair.
Wiggle-wiggle, everything is wiggle-wiggle.
And... and also look at my hair.
Look at my hair.
Wait,
Look at that.
Nice! Nice!
And also, what, can you guys see?
And also, wait, can you guys see?
My ear.
Look at that, my ear.
There.
Isn't it nice? I love it.
I love it.
Hey!
Don't...
No.
No-uh.
I see, I see a lot of people like want the moonwalk.
I see... I see a lot of people who want the moonwalk.
It's been a while. I don't know how to do it.
That's how we do it, baby!
Tapi papi karena ini karpet ya, jadi kalau moonwalk itu agak-agak agak sulit, syung syung syung syung syung syung gitu.
Papi, because this is a carpet, you know,
so if you moonwalk it's a bit difficult...
It's- it's so hard, but yeah.
Woah! Woah!
It's a flawless moonwalk though!
I mean, after all, I am the celestial moon.
You want to take a screenshot? Sure, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna pause. Wild pause?
What is that? Oh my god!
Super chat! I'm gonna pose like I get a super chat then.
Super chat! I'm gonna pose like
I get a super chat then.
Yeah! Woah! Woah! Woah! Woah!
Woah, there's a lot of super chat coming!
What is this?
Oh! Woah! I got balls in my hand!
I got balls in my hand! There's a lot of balls in my room, and I'm liking it.
There's a lot of balls in my room,
and I'm liking it.
Yeah! Crystal balls!
Nice, isn't it? Mhm-hm-hm-hm...
Nice, isn't it? Mhm-hm-hm...
Okay! I- I have a lot of things, you know.
I cannot- I cannot look all of the super chat.
I cannot- I cannot look at all the super chats.
So I'm gonna keep it, I'm gonna keep it, and I will sing a lot more for you.
So I'm gonna keep it, and I will sing a lot more for you.
But I think my head a little bit dizzy because of the- of the balls.
But I think my head's a little bit dizzy
because of the- of the balls.
Probably the balls is coming to me so...
Probably the balls are coming to me, so...
when you look up at the night sky what do you see ?
When you look up at the night sky, what do you see?
the glowing beauty in the twilight it 's no mystery
The glowing beauty in the twilight, it's no mystery.
now watch me set the scene , i 'll light it all up
Now watch me set the scene, I'll light it all up.
when the time has come , i 'll be rising high
When the time has come, I'll be rising high.
longing for me like a lifeline
whenever you see my shine
i 'll catch your eye
I'll catch your eye.
it 's pulling you in like gravity
It's pulling you in like gravity,
you will be bowing on your knees , yeah
you will be bowing on your knees, yeah.
pulling you in , close to me , watch my glory and might
Pulling you in, close to me, watch my glory and might.
following me like a high tide
my reign will never stop
the tide begins to rise up to the top
let my power ignite
following me like a high tide
woah , oh
woah, oh.
i can be a bright enigma
it 's no surprise
it's no surprise.
it 's no surprise , yeah
It's no surprise, yeah.
but you'll give in to the brilliance like a moth to a light
playing hard to get , but i ain't patient , you'll succumb to my blinding radiance , yeah
Playing hard to get, but I ain't patient, you'll succumb to my blinding radiance, yeah.
when you look up at the night sky what do you see ? my shine an effulgent sight
When you look up at the night sky, what do you see? My shine an effulgent sight.
it 's pulling you in like gravity , you will be bowing on your knees , yeah
It's pulling you in like gravity, you will be bowing on your knees, yeah.
pulling you in , close to me , watch my glory and might
Pulling you in, close to me, watch my glory and might.
following me like a high tide , my reign will never stop
Following me like a high tide, my reign will never stop.
the tide begins to rise up to the top , let my power ignite
The tide begins to rise up to the top, let my power ignite.
following me like a high tide , woah , oh
Following me like a high tide, woah, oh.
when you look up at the night sky
what do you see ?
what do you see?
the glowing beauty in the twilight
it ’s no mystery
it's no mystery
now watch me set the scene
i ’ll light it all up
I'll light it all up
when the time has come i ’ll be rising high
when the time has come, I'll be rising high
longing for me like a lifeline
whenever you see my shine
i ’ll catch your eye
I'll catch your eye
it ’s pulling you in like gravity
it's pulling you in like gravity
you will be bowing on your knees , yeah
you will be bowing on your knees, yeah
pulling you in close to me
watch my glory and might
following me like a high tide
my reign will never stop
the tide begins to rise up to the top
let my power ignite
following me like a high tide
ooo ohh
i can be a bright enigma
it ’s no surprise
it's no surprise
but you ’ll give in to the brilliance like a moth to a light
but you'll give in to the brilliance like a moth to a light
playing hard to get
but i ain ’t patient
but I ain't patient
you ’ll succumb to my blinding radiance yeah
you'll succumb to my blinding radiance, yeah
when you look up at the night sky
what do you see ?
what do you see?
my shine !
my shine!
an effulgent sight
it ’s pulling you in like gravity
it's pulling you in like gravity
you will be bowing on your knees , yeah
you will be bowing on your knees, yeah
pulling you in close to me
watch my glory and might
following me like a high tide
my reign will never stop
the tide begins to rise up to the top
let my power ignite
following me like a high tide
ooo ohh
i shine the brightest in the night
the way the waves come nigh
ohh
ooo ohh
Muna!
Moona!
Bangun!
Wake up!
Hmm?
Where am I? Muna di mana?
Where am I? Where is Moona?
Risu!
Muna, kamu, oh my god!
Moona, you, oh my god!
Kamu tahu, kamu harus terbangun secara menyeluruh.
You know, you have to wake up completely.
Maka dari itu kita harus bernyanyi sekali lagi.
Therefore, we must sing once more.
Kalau gitu, gimana kalau kita nyanyi... Preserved Roses?
If so, how about we sing... Preserved Roses?
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして儚い花の
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream,
偽りが切ない 閉じ込めた生命(いのち)の
the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
孤独を君に捧げる Preserved Rose
I dedicate this loneliness to you, Preserved Rose.
翳りの奥溢れるものを 人と 変えているだけ
We only change what overflows from the shadows into human form.
全てが「冷たすぎる」なんて 指を 解かせないで
Don't unclasp your fingers, saying everything is 'too cold'.
光と闇の どちらにでも居れる
We can exist within either light or darkness.
恐がらないで 望まぬ朝は もう来ない
Don't be afraid—the morning you dread will never come.
鮮やかだけを 繰り返し 繋がり 終わり 君はまた...
Repeating only brilliance, connecting and ending, you once again...
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして儚い花の
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream,
偽りが切ない 拒む世界を傷付ける
the painful deception wounds the world that rejects it.
願うなら魅せる だから遠く消えないで
If you wish, I'll enchant you, so don't fade away into the distance.
君が見る明日の 新しい息吹を
Greet with open arms the new breath of tomorrow
伸ばした腕に迎える 離さない
that you will see; I won't let go.
無傷のまま溶け出す熱を 愛を 弄る想い
Letting out the heat undamaged, toying with love and feelings,
作りモノの微笑み疑う 罪に 囚われ ながら
imprisoned by the sin of doubting artificial smiles,
汚れてしまう 前に行くと言った
I decided to go before becoming stained.
やがて零れて 散らばる水に 華やかに
In the water that will soon spill and scatter, so brilliantly
ココロを映し 出せば なら
reflecting our hearts if we can,
途絶える歌と 引き換えに
in exchange for the fading song,
激しい色を注いで 飾り立てた幻を
pouring violent colors into the decorated illusion—
君が信じるなら 真実だって越えられるだろう
if you believe in it, you can surpass even truth.
移る時間(とき)を止めて 朽ちる術も知らないで
Stopping the passage of time, knowing not even how to decay,
血を流すその手は 閉じ込めた生命(いのち)の
those hands that bleed present to you
孤独を君に捧げる 求めている
the loneliness of a caged life, searching for it.
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして儚い花の
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream,
偽りが切ない 拒む世界を傷付ける
the painful deception wounds the world that rejects it.
願うなら魅せる だから遠く消えないで
If you wish, I'll enchant you, so don't fade away into the distance.
君が見る明日の 新しい息吹を
Greet with open arms the new breath of tomorrow
伸ばした腕に迎える 離さない
that you will see; I won't let go.
傷のまま溶け出す熱を 惑わす想い
The heat thawing out undamaged, bewildering feelings,
孤独を君に捧げる 囚われながら
imprisoned while dedicating loneliness to you,
汚れ切ってしまふ前に
before becoming completely stained,
ときめいて 流れてゆく
pulsating and flowing away.
心をおとし入れるなら
If we plunge our hearts into it,
激しい音で切り裂いて
slashing through with intense sound,
君が信じるなら 進み続けて超えるだろう
if you believe, we will keep moving forward to surpass it.
震える呼吸を止めて 知り尽くしても知らないで
Stopping our trembling breath, knowing nothing even when knowing all,
孤独を君に捧げる 求めている
dedicating this loneliness to you, searching for it.
短い夢を重ねて
Overlapping short dreams,
永遠にして逝く花の
flowers fading into eternity—
嘘が切ない
their falsehood is poignant.
閉じ込めた生命の 孤独を君に捧げる
I offer the solitude of trapped life to you,
願うなら魅せてだから遠く消えないで
if you wish, charm me, so do not disappear far away.
君が見る明日の 新しい息吹を
The new breath of tomorrow that you see,
伸ばした腕に迎える 離さない
I welcome with outstretched arms and will not let go.
無傷まま溶け出す 熱を 愛を
The heat and love melting out unblemished—
弄る想い 作り笑い疑う
toying feelings, fake smiles, doubtful—
罪に囚われながら 汚れてしまう
trapped in sin, we become stained.
Sepertinya Moona sudah tersucikan!
It seems Moona has been purified!
Bentar!
Wait!
Wah, wah, wah, wah!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Thank you banget loh Risu!
Thank you so much, Risu!
Ckya!
Tahu gak sih, kenapa Moona milih Preserved Rose ini?
You know why Moona chose Preserved Rose?
Kenapa?
Why?
Pengen aja sih.
Just felt like it.
Biar biar bangun gitu kan, iya biar bangun biar wah gitu kannya.
To wake up, you know? Yeah, to wake up and feel awesome.
Iya, lagian kayaknya keren banget tuh kalau Preserved Rose kita kan nyanyi, ya udah kita nyanyi kan saja.
Yeah, besides, it'd be cool if we sang Preserved Rose, so we just sang it.
Tuh!
Right!
Anyway, ini kan kita lagi berdua nih, mumpung berdua, bolehlah kita promosi teman kita besoknya, dia juga 3D showcase loh.
Anyway, since we're together right now, we can promote our friend for tomorrow, she's also having a 3D showcase.
Siapa ni? Siapa?
Who's that? Who?
3D showcase besok itu ada Iofi, teman-teman.
Tomorrow's 3D showcase is Iofi, guys!
Yeay!
Yay!
Kalau begitu, karena Moona sudah bangun, saatnya Risu adios.
Well then, since Moona is awake, it's time for Risu to say adios.
Adios! Bye-bye! Next time, bye-bye.
Wah, gila keren banget.
Man, that was crazy cool.
Risu cukup semangat juga ya, semoga nanti 3D case-nya juga showcase-nya juga semangat, okay.
Risu was quite enthusiastic too, hope her 3D showcase is just as energetic, okay.
Hah, Moona juga masih semangat nih, jadi semoga kalian masih bersemangat ya.
Ah, Moona is still energized too, so hope you guys are still energized too.
Kita nikmati acara malam ini.
Let's enjoy tonight's event.
Selanjutnya,
Next,
Moona pengen nyanyi lagi nih.
Moona wants to sing again.
You guys ready?
Palette.
風に吹かれて 誰も気づかぬように
Blown by the wind, so no one notices,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
a monochrome world where nothing stands out.
色を足しても 何も見えなくて
Even adding color, I see nothing,
まるで私は 息を止めいていた
as if I had stopped breathing.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は
It's fine now, even if it's far, I want to make it come true—
こんな世界 想いも抱きしめていたいのに
though I want to embrace my feelings in this world.
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味はこの胸に 輝いている ストーリー
The meaning of staying on the dream's canvas shines in this heart as a story.
望みよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は
Oh desire, even if far, I want to make it come true—
こんな世界 想いも
though I want to embrace my feelings in this world.
抱きしめていたいのに
Though I want to embrace them,
夢の中で 描き続けていたいのに
I want to keep drawing them within my dreams.
この胸に今 輝いているストーリー
A story that now shines brightly in this heart.
与えることに 意味などないけど
Even if giving has no real meaning,
拾い集めた カケラ失うの？
will I lose the fragments I picked up?
そして夜はその冷たさを
And the night melts its coldness,
溶かして手を伸ばした
reaching out its hand.
もういいよ 遠くても 届けたい 私は
It's fine now, even if it's far, I want to deliver it—
受け入れてく 涙も 抱きしめていたいのに
though I want to embrace even the tears I accept.
夢のキャンバスに 心込めるのは
Putting my heart into the canvas of dreams,
この空に描き出すの ストーリー
I draw out a story in this sky.
そして夜はその冷たさを
And the night melts its coldness,
溶かして手を伸ばした
reaching out its hand.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は
It's fine now, even if it's far, I want to make it come true.
私の黄金の世界
My golden world...
想いを言葉で包んで
wrapping my feelings in words...
夢のキャンバスに
on the canvas of dreams
色を足していく
adding colors,
この胸に今輝いて
shining now in this heart.
強くなくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong,
壊れかけてもいい
it's okay to be on the verge of breaking.
この心は永遠に羽ばたいて
This heart will forever soar,
響くように塗り替えていくパレット
repainting into a resonating palette.
皆様、ありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much!
すっごく嬉しくて
I'm so, so happy!
胸がいっぱいで…おめでとう！
My heart is so full... Congratulations!
You know, today, we're singing your,
you know, song Palette.
Oh my god, I'm so excited. Palette is one...
Singing with you is like, aaah! めっちゃめちゃ嬉しいわ！
Singing with you is like, aaah! I'm so happy!
ありがとうございます！ Thank you so much!
Thank you so much!
いやもう、いっぱい、これからも一緒に歌おう！
Let's keep singing together a lot more!
Together! Singing! Yeah, yeah, yeah, ikuyo!
Together! Singing! Yeah, let's go!
Oh my god, thank you so much, I'm so nervous.
You know, thanks for making time for meeting, thank you.
We're both thank you, yeah! Many, many thank you!
いやね、むーなにね、誘われて、一緒に歌おうって言ってくれて、本当に、もう嬉しかったよ、ありがとう。
You invited me to sing together, I'm so happy, thank you.
はい。じゃあね、ということでね。うん。
Yes. So, with that being said... um.
ということで、皆さん、まだまだたくさん聴いていってくださいね！とわ、ここでバイバイ！むーな、頑張って！
Everyone, please keep listening to lots more!
頑張っていきます！バイバイ！
I will! Bye-bye!
Waah, waah, waah. Macha macha, thank you so much, Towa-sama.
Waah, thank you so much, Towa-sama.
Next, I want to sing a song. Mau pengen nyanyi lagu, ini lagu dari Indonesia.
Next, I want to sing a song from Indonesia.
And I want to show you to the overseas, for Japan also, to hear this Indonesian song.
I want to show you to the overseas, for Japan also...
So, next song is... Matahariku.
Tertutup sudah pintu-pintu hatiku
Closed are the doors of my heart,
Yang pernah dibuka waktu, hanya untukmu
that once were opened by time, only for you.
Kini kau pergi dari hidupku
Now you have gone from my life,
Ku harus relakan mu walau tak mau
I must let you go even though I don't want to.
Berjuta warna pelangi di dalam hati
Millions of rainbow colors in my heart
Sejenak luluh bergeming menjauh pergi
instantly melting, standing still, walking away.
Tak ada lagi cahaya suci
There is no more sacred light,
Semua nada beranjak, aku terdiam sepi
all notes step away, I am left in silent stillness.
Dengarlah, matahariku, suara tangisanku
Listen, my sun, to the sound of my crying,
Ku bersedih karena panah cinta menusuk jantungku
I am grieving because love pierced my heart.
Ucapkan, matahariku, puisi tentang hidupku
Speak, my sun, a poem about my life,
Tentang ku yang tak mampu menaklukkan waktu
about me who cannot conquer time.
tertutup sudah pintu, pintu hatiku
The door is closed, my heart's door
yang pernah dibuka waktu, hanya untukmu
Which was once opened by time, just for you
kini kau pergi dari hidupku
Now you're gone from my life
ku harus relakanmu walau aku tak mau
I must let you go even though I don't want to
berjuta warna pelangi di dalam hati
Millions of rainbow colors inside my heart
sejenak luluh bergeming menjauh pergi
Dissolved away for a moment, fading away
tak ada lagi cahaya suci
There is no more pure light
semua nada beranjak, aku terdiam sepi
Every tone departs, I stand in silent solitude
dengarlah matahariku, suara tangisanku
Listen, my sun, to the sound of my crying
ku bersedih karena panah cinta menusuk jantungku
I am sad because the arrow of love pierced my heart
ucapkan matahariku puisi tentang hidupku
Speak, my sun, a poem about my life
tentang ku yang tak mampu menaklukkan waktu
About me who cannot conquer time
berjuta warna pelangi di dalam hati
Millions of rainbow colors inside my heart
sejenak luluh bergeming menjauh pergi
Dissolved away for a moment, fading away
tak ada lagi cahaya suci
There is no more pure light
semua nada beranjak, aku terdiam sepi
Every tone departs, I stand in silent solitude
dengarlah matahariku, suara tangisanku
Listen, my sun, to the sound of my crying
ku bersedih karena panah cinta menusuk jantungku
I am sad because the arrow of love pierced my heart
ucapkan matahariku puisi tentang hidupku
Speak, my sun, a poem about my life
tentang ku yang tak mampu menaklukkan waktu
About me who cannot conquer time
dengarlah matahariku, suara tangisanku
Listen, my sun, to the sound of my crying
ku bersedih karena panah cinta menusuk jantungku
I am sad because the arrow of love pierced my heart
dengarlah matahariku, suara tangisanku
Listen, my sun, to the sound of my crying
ku bersedih karena panah cinta menusuk jantungku
I am sad because the arrow of love pierced my heart
ucapkan matahariku puisi tentang hidupku
Speak, my sun, a poem about my life
tentang ku yang tak mampu menaklukkan waktu
About me who cannot conquer time
mornin' mornin' yaa
Morning, morning!
pagi pagi pagi...
Morning, morning, morning...
warna cerah yang terlihat
These visible bright colors
diriku mahir sembunyi rasa
formed by my well-concealed feelings
sebenarnya hitam pekat
In reality, they are all pitch black
ku tutup rapat, jadi rahasia
I sealed them as a secret
satu dua kali, ku tak apa-apa
Once or twice, I can accept
kamu pikir hidupku baik-baik saja
But did you think my life is all okay?
siapa yang peduli, ku punya air mata
Nobody cares, I have tears
kamu hanya pinta diri berikan tawa
You just ask me to give a smile
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
wajah riang ku perisai jitu
My cheerful look is an absolute shield
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
tapi sampai kapan ku begitu
But how long should I keep it?
malam hari berwahana
During restless night
pikiran liarku juaranya
My spiraling mind takes over
bukan ku tak berusaha
Not because I gave no effort
ingin kulepas sekuat tenaga
I just want to let it go with all my might
satu dua kali, ku tak apa-apa
Once or twice, I can accept
kamu pikir hidupku baik-baik saja
But did you think my life is all okay?
siapa yang peduli, ku punya air mata
Nobody cares, I have tears
kamu hanya pinta diri berikan tawa
You just ask me to give a smile
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
wajah riang ku perisai jitu
My cheerful look is an absolute shield
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
tapi sampai kapan ku begitu
But how long should I keep it?
aku bulan yang terangi
I am the shining moon
malam-malam mu yang sepi
Illuminating your lonely nights
lalu siapa yang temani
But who will keep me company?
rasa gelisah kupikul sendiri
I carry these restless feelings on my own
ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha
ha - ho
ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha
ha - hm, yeah
ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha
ha - oh
ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha
hu - hu-hu
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
wajah riang ku perisai jitu
My cheerful look is an absolute shield
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
tapi sampai kapan ku begitu
But how long should I keep it?
ha - ha , ha - ha , ha - ha
Ha - ha, ha - ha, ha - ha
wajah riang ku perisai jitu
My cheerful look is an absolute shield
tapi sampai kapan ku begitu
But how long should I keep it?
This is my newest original song,
hehehe...
I'm so nervous! I'm so nervous, wait wait.
I don't know, if I make a mistake, I might make a mistake, oh my god.
But anyway, that's my newest song!
What do you guys think?
Jadi itu adalah lagu original song pertama yang bahasanya Indonesia.
So that is the first original song in Indonesian.
Ya, yang bahasanya Indonesia akhirnya, guys.
Yes, finally in Indonesian, guys.
Ya, ditunggu aja ya, nanti rilisnya kapan-kapan.
Yeah, just wait for it, it will be released sometime.
Secepatnya, secepatnya, nanti bakal rilis secepatnya.
As soon as possible, it will be released as soon as possible.
semoga kalian suka sama lagunya. I hope you guys really like it, I hope you like the new song,
I hope you guys really like it, I hope you like the new song,
the Indonesian song that I am... the one that I'm working on right now. Thank you so much.
the Indonesian song that I am working on right now. Thank you so much.
So what do you guys think for tonight?
What do you guys think about my... my whole showcase? Do you guys like it?
What do you guys think about my whole showcase? Do you guys like it?
Do you guys like it? Aw.
Anyway... anyway, you guys want to see?
Right now... right now, I'm on the stage of Hololive Indonesia stage.
Right now, I'm on the Hololive Indonesia stage.
This is... massive!
Sorry, this is so massive. I mean, look at that! Wow, there's... there's so many thing. I have moon in my back,
Sorry, this is so massive. Look at that! Wow, I have a moon in the back,
and we also have kind of like a pool... um, boats...
and we also have kind of like a... boats...
Sheep, I mean ship! And... and also we have kind of like a bolt, two bolts in the leven the right.
Ship! I mean sheep! And also we have kind of like a bolt... two bolts in the right.
in the lavender light! (laughs)
And... and also we have like Indonesian cimo... symbols in the back. Yeah, it's... it's so beautiful.
And we have like Indonesian symbols in the back, yeah. It's so beautiful.
Um, this Hololive Indonesia... arena right now... I have a galaxy because it's follow my... my team right now.
Um, this Hololive Indonesia arena right now... I have a galaxy because it's for my team right now.
So I'm... I really like it. I mean, look at that!
So I really like it. I mean, look at that!
Oh my god, guys! Look at that! Look at how beautiful it is.
Anyway, I just want to thank you for you guys... for waiting for this long... um, months.
Anyway, I just want to thank you for you guys for waiting for these long months.
So thank you so much... uh, for... for waiting for a long time. Thank you for your patience, and thank you for watching, and thank you for everything.
So thank you so much for waiting for a long time, thank you for your patience, and thank you for watching.
Then... um... I will... I'm asking you, what do you guys about... what do you guys think?
Then... I'm asking you, what do you guys think?
What do you guys think? But before we end this stream, I just want to tell you that tomorrow...
tomorrow... We're going to have something...
[Airani Iofeteen 3D Showcase - September 17]
Iofeteen will have a 3D showcase tomorrow, September 17 at 8 PM. It's the same time, so...
Iofeteen will have a 3D showcase tomorrow, September 17 at 8 PM, at the same time.
So hey guys, don't forget to come to her 3D showcase, because I wonder... what it will be. I mean, she said there's gonna be a lots... a lot of things. Yes. Yes.
So hey guys, don't forget to come to her 3D showcase, because I wonder what it will be. She said there's going to be a lot of things!
Jadi, terima kasih semua. Jangan lupa ya datang ke 3D showcase-nya Iofi. Dan habis itu ada... habis Iofi ada Risu.
So, thank you everyone. Don't forget to come to Iofi's 3D showcase. And after Iofi there is Risu.
Jadi, jangan lupa ya datang. Bye-bye! Thank you semuanya! Yay!
So, don't forget to come. Bye-bye! Thank you everyone! Yay!
Thank you for waiting 17 months! After a long time finally, I can show you my 3D Showcase!
Moona Hoshinova 3D Showcase